### **Curriculum Vitae**

Ryunosuke "Ryan" Goto, M.D.

Resident Physician, Department of Pediatrics at the University of Tokyo Hospital

Email: rgoto@m.u-tokyo.ac.jp



I am a Pediatrics Resident at the University of Tokyo Hospital and Nagano Children's Hospital. After receiving primary and secondary education in the United Kingdom and the United States, I received my M.D. from the University of Tokyo in 2019. I have conducted numerous studies on social determinants of health (war, adverse childhood experiences, and socioeconomic status, among others) and their relationship with development, mental health, and chronic disease. I am also interested in advancing precision medicine by tailoring interventions to meet the unique needs of individuals based on their socioeconomic and health circumstances. My work has been published in *The Lancet, JAMA Pediatrics*, and *Pediatrics*, among other journals.

### **Education** M.D., Faculty of Medicine, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan

04/2013 - 03/2019

#### Monta Vista High School, Cupertino, CA, USA

08/2008 - 06/2012

#### **Work Experience**

#### Nagano Children's Hospital

Resident Physician, Pediatrics

10/2021 -

#### The University of Tokyo Hospital

Resident Physician, Pediatrics 04/2019 – 09/2021

#### **IBM Research**

*Research Intern* 02/2019 - 03/2019

Explored possible applications of automated connected speech analysis in the detection of pragmatic language impairment in individuals with autistic spectrum disorder

## **United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East** *Intern*

07/2017 - 09/2017

Quality improvement and research on the dissemination and implementation of an electronic maternal and child health handbook application, e-MCH Handbook For more information on the e-MCH Handbook:

http://libopac.jica.go.jp/images/report/1000036631 02.pdf

#### **Ongoing research**

#### Social network analysis for prevention of social isolation

In collaboration with University of California, Los Angeles, USA. 08/2022-

#### Machine Learning Detects Heterogeneous Effects of Medicaid on Depression: Oregon Health Insurance Experiment.

In collaboration with University of California, Los Angeles, USA.

#### Heterogeneous effects of antidepressants on suicide

In collaboration with the Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Norway and Massachusetts Institute of Technology, USA. 03/2021-

Longitudinal effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on the well-being of children In collaboration with Oxford University, United Kingdom and the National Center for Child Health and Development, Japan. 12/2020-

Social determinants of COVID-19: a mediation analysis of vaccination rates In collaboration with Harvard University, USA and Kyoto University, Japan. 12/2020-

#### **Publications**

#### **Peer-reviewed publications**

**Ryunosuke Goto**, Aurelie Piedvache, Mayumi Hangai, Yui Yamaoka, Mariko Sampei, Naomi Sawada, Yusuke Okubo, Kyoko Tanaka, Naho Morisaki, Mariko Hosozawa. Time trends in emotional well-being and self-esteem in children and adolescents during the COVID-19 pandemic. *Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Mental Health*. 2022 Nov 23;16:89.

**Ryunosuke Goto\*,** Irina Pinchuk\*, Oleksiy Kolodezhny, Nataliia Pimenova, Norbert Skokauskas. Mental health services in Ukraine during the early phases of the 2022 Russian invasion. *British Journal of Psychiatry (in press).* (\*joint first authors)

**Ryunosuke Goto,** Yusuke Okubo, Norbert Skokauskas. Reasons and trends in youth's suicide rates during the COVID-19 pandemic. *The Lancet Regional Health – Western Pacific.* 2022 Oct 1;27:100567.

Irina Pinchuk\*, **Ryunosuke Goto**\*, Nataliia Pimenova, Oleksiy Kolodezhny, Anthony P. S. Guerrero, Norbert Skokauskas. Mental health of helpline staff in Ukraine during the 2022 Russian invasion. *European Psychiatry*. 2022 Aug 10; 65(1),E45. (\*joint first authors)

**Ryunosuke Goto,** Roch Nianogo, Yusuke Okubo, Kosuke Inoue. Evaluation of Obesity Trends Among US Adolescents by Socioeconomic Status, 1999-2018. *JAMA Pediatrics.* 2022 June 21;176(9):937–940.

Yosuke Eriguchi, Xiaoxue Gu, Naoto Aoki, Maiko Nonaka, **Ryunosuke Goto**, Hitoshi Kuwabara, Yukiko Kano, Kiyoto Kasai. A 2-year longitudinal follow-up of quantitative assessment neck tics in Tourette's syndrome. *Plos One.* 2021 Dec 30;16(12):e0261560.

**Ryunosuke Goto,** Natsumi Matsuda, Maiko Nonaka, Yu Hamamoto, Yosuke Eriguchi, Mayu Fujiwara, Akane Suzuki, Yukari Yokoyama, Yukiko Kano. The Gilles de la Tourette Syndrome-Quality of Life Scale (GTS-QOL): A Validation in Japanese Patients. *Frontiers in Psychiatry.* 2022 Jan 3;12:797037.

**Ryunosuke Goto,** Yoko Watanabe, Ako Yamazaki, Masatoshi Sugita, Satoru Takeda, Masao Nakabayashi, Yasuhide Nakamura. Can digital health technologies

exacerbate the health gap? A clustering analysis of mothers' opinions toward digitizing the maternal and child health handbook. *SSM-Population Health*. 2021 Oct;16:100935.

**Ryunosuke Goto,** Thomas Frodl, Norbert Skokauskas. Armed Conflict and Early Childhood Development in 12 Low- and Middle-Income Countries. *Pediatrics*. 2021 Sep;148(3),e2021050332.

**Ryunosuke Goto,** Ryo Inuzuka, Takahiro Shindo, Yoshiyuki Namai, Yoichiro Oda, Yutaka Harita, Akira Oka. Relationship between post-IVIG IgG levels and clinical outcomes in Kawasaki disease patients: new insight into the mechanism of action of IVIG. *Clinical Rheumatology*. 2020 Dec;39: 3747-55.

Seif Nasir\*, **Ryunosuke Goto**\*, Akiko Kitamura, Sahar Alafeef, Ghada Ballout, Majed Hababeh, Junko Kiriya, Akihiro Seita, Masamine Jimba. Dissemination and implementation of the e-MCHHandbook, UNRWA's newly released maternal and child health mobile application: a cross-sectional study. *BMJ Open.* 2020;10:e034885. (\*joint first authors)

**Ryunosuke Goto**, Miyuki Fujio, Natsumi Matsuda, Mayu Fujiwara, Marina Nobuyoshi, Maiko Nonaka, Toshiaki Kono, Masaki Kojima, Norbert Skokauskas, Yukiko Kano. The effects of comorbid Tourette symptoms on distress caused by compulsive-like behavior in very young children: a cross-sectional study. *Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Mental Health*. 2019 Jun 28;13:28.

#### **Other publications**

Ryunosuke Goto, Yoko Watanabe, Yasuhide Nakamura. JAPAN: Digitization of MCH Handbook and the socioeconomic disparity in health. *Japan International Cooperation Agency Technical Brief*. Jun 2022. <a href="https://www.jica.go.jp/activities/issues/health/mch\_handbook/ku57pq000028koi9-att/technical\_brief\_41.pdf">https://www.jica.go.jp/activities/issues/health/mch\_handbook/ku57pq000028koi9-att/technical\_brief\_41.pdf</a>.

**Ryunosuke Goto**, Anthony P. S. Guerrero, Mario Speranza, Daniel Fung, Campbell Paul, Norbert Skokauskas. War is a public health emergency. *The Lancet.* 2022 Apr 2; 399(1302):1302.

Akiko Kitamura, **Ryunosuke Goto**, Seif Nasir, Majed Hababeh, Ghada Ballout, Akihiro Seita. JORDAN: UNRWA's electric MCH Handbook application for Palestine Refugees. *Japan International Cooperation Agency Technical Brief*. August 2017. <a href="http://libopac.jica.go.jp/images/report/1000036631\_02.pdf">http://libopac.jica.go.jp/images/report/1000036631\_02.pdf</a>.

## Presentations and

### **Oral Conference Presentations**

Talks

Ryunosuke Goto, Thomas Frodl, Norbert Skokauskas. Armed Conflict and Early Childhood Development in 12 Low- and Middle-Income Countries. American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) National Conference and Exhibition (International Conference), Philadelphia, PA, United States (virtual). October, 2021.

**Ryunosuke Goto**, Miyuki Fujio, Natsumi Matsuda, Mayu Fujiwara, Norbert Skokauskas, Yukiko Kano. Effects of comorbid Tourette symptoms on distress by compulsive-like behavior in very young children. **24**th **World Congress of the** 

International Association for Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Allied Professions (IACAPAP) (International Conference), Singapore. December, 2020.

Ryunosuke Goto, Seif Nasir, Akiko Kitamura, Majed Hababeh, Ghada Ballout, Junko Kiriya, Akihiro Seita, Masamine Jimba. Dissemination and implementation of the e-MCH Handbook, the potential role of m-Health in improving health equity in a refugee setting: A cross-sectional study. American Public Health Association (APHA) Annual Meeting (International Conference), San Diego, CA, United States. November, 2018.

#### **Invited Talks**

Ryunosuke Goto, Akihiro Nishi. Social network analysis and network interventions in society, human development, and health research. *Eunice Kennedy Shriver* National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD) Social and Behavioral Sciences Branch Seminar Series. November 10, 2022.

Ryunosuke Goto. What changes can the electronic Maternal and Child Health Handbook bring to health care? An example from Jordan. 4<sup>th</sup> annual Maternal and Child Health Handbook Forum, Tokyo, Japan. October 8, 2019. An overview on the electronic Maternal and Child Health Handbook in Jordan and

Ryunosuke Goto. Social common capital and health: from a global perspective.

A presentation on the electronic Maternal and Child Health Handbook in Jordan and how it contributed to health equity for Palestine refugees

#### **Qualifications**

#### **TOEFL iBT 118/120**

Palestine refugees

09/2017

**United States Medical Licensing Examination (USMLE) Step 2 Clinical Skills** 11/2018

# Honors and Awards

The University of Tokyo Hospital Department of Pediatrics Research Award

Awarded the top researcher of the year in the department

Nikkei SDGs Forum, Tokyo, Japan. May 9, 2019.

## Donald J. Cohen Fellowship Program for International Scholars in Child and Adolescent Mental Health

12/2020

Awarded to emerging leaders in child and adolescent mental health throughout the world, and is awarded at the International Association for Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Allied Professions (IACAPAP) Congress

## The University of Tokyo Faculty of Medicine Dean's Award 01/2018

Awarded to the top three out of about 120 students in the Class of 2019, based on excellence in clinical rotations

## The University of Tokyo Osamu Otsubo Fellowship 01/2018

A scholarship awarded to top students who aspire to receive medical education abroad

### The University of Tokyo Go Global Scholarship

Autumn 2017 and Spring 2018

A scholarship awarded to top students to study abroad

# Pigeon Foundation Scholarship for Aspiring Pediatricians, Obstetricians, and Gynecologists

04/2017 - 03/2019

A scholarship awarded to top medical students who aim to become pediatricians, obstetricians, or gynecologists